welcome back everyone
and today we are going to start with the most valuable lesson we will ever be taught in GTNH
rely on the old way of doing things
just because you unlocked a new way of doing things a little bit more efficiently
it doesn't mean you have to start using it right away
indeed, in the last episode we figured out we can get three times the amount of plates out of the same ore by using those steam machines
the issue is that while we get a way better yield by using those machines
those machines are also incredibly slow
so, we are going to ignore those machines and go back to the good old Vanilla furnaces
which we are powering with the creosote oil leftover from the coke ovens which we have to use somehow
using the hammer, we are getting so many resources anyways that that's a sufficient way of processing ores is not a big deal
and with that, we have so many ingots that we can just smash those with a hammer
and stock up iron plates just like that
and while we could work on the main objective of these ages just like that
we are not going to use those iron plates for that main objective
what we are using those plates for is to upgrade our single block workshop into a multi block workshop
we are crafting so much stuff that even NEI auto crafting is too slow
and after crafting a bunch of parts
we can start actually building something
so, the first thing we will have is a steam tank
this will act as a buffer for the steam we produce
i know it sounds weird, storing steam in a tank, it should like condense and fall down as water
but don't think too much about it
um, this time i'm going to be lit on the roof of my house
because i'm going to do solar boilers, my favorite way of making energy
but right now that's going to be it
then i already prepared a two big of a burning box
i think i'm going to use it like that at the beginning
but soon enough, i will turn these into bigger size
can be also one block taller
but for the moment, just this one
OK, the bigger you make this tank
the more it takes to heat up
i want a bigger tank too
but i'm going to get steam press before finishing the rest
then to make water
the power of this one probably it's enough to use that water tank
but i want to make right away the better water pump
this one can handle way more machines
that we go
we pipe it up so it can actually get some steam to work
OK, the downside of this water pump is that it takes some steam to work
it makes way more water than using the other tanks
but it does require a little bit of power in the form of steam
and then we need some water here to kick start this one
there you go
and we can start heating it up
once again, has to reach one hundred degrees before it makes any steam
so first remember this one, the hotter it is the more it makes steam
uh, there are other boilers
but i like this one
and we must not forget to pipe the water
to the boiler
and here i also have a handy water pipe for the future
usually i heavily suggest taking all of the pipe to make it flow nicer
OK, once the steam reaches half
it will start pushing into the tank
this tank has some valves
this tank is made out of three blocks
there is the main structure block, glass which is like the cheaper
and there are those valves that allow you to input/output
the output is only from the bottom
the tank automatically outputs from the bottom
so you can attach a pipe on the bottom of this one, and the tank will push steam into that pipe
but it does not do that on the sides or on the top
so as we were saying on the bottom soon enough we would have some steam
and then we can run this steam to the machines
want to keep some of the old machines too
but i'm going to build multi blocks too
i mean we already have those machines
so may as well keep those for a few times we need to craft a little bit of things
those bigger multi blocks work in batches
but those multi blocks are also quite expensive to build
so we may as well start saving some materials by using these small multi blocks
which we can now power a little bit easier with the new boiler
at this point of the game
we probably also want to have a little bit of automation
so, with this machine, the automation consists of just using hopper
so hopper in stuff, hopper out into chests, the output
and with that, we can now more easily craft some more expensive machines that would work way better
the first one i want to do is the steam grinder
that is because the single block maserator is basically impossible to use
it's just too slow
while the forge hammer and alloy smelter are the same I will say for the moment
so, you prepare all of the blocks required
just prepare everything
then you can manually build it
or you can just craft one of those multiblock structure hologram projector
and then you click on the thing and it builds for you
so my suggestion is first figure out where you want the hatches
and then once you decided where to put the hatches build the machine
by the way, the amount of those you use when you try to build the machine will change the tier of the machine
so if you click with a single spell
it will do a level one machine
if you click with a stack of two
it will try to make a tier two
for instance with this multiblock tier one means bronze, tier two means steel
the next thing we have to worry about is the pipe to hook it up
now to figure out which pipe to use is not too easy
right now you probably can only use bronze pipes
and each pipe has a different capacity
now if you look at the controller usage you can get an idea of how much steam it could take
the issue is that some recipe use way more steam than then the others
so figuring out what pipe to use can be tricky
for the moment, i'm just going to use some normal pipes
and in the future i will decide if and what pipe to use
and by the way, by now i can also upgrade the tank
and i have already upgraded the boiler because this small one was not keeping up even with the simple box
and there we have our bigger tank with two thousand buckets of capacity
another thing you may want to pay attention to is that this one is quite efficient
the steam usage you see here is not the one you should be looking at when you look at the multiblock
because this multiblock has a speed buff, a steam usage discount
but most importantly some parallels
so if you look for example at the
random iron ore
all of the ores should have the same amount of steam used
which is supposed to be eighty liters per second
but as you can see here
it's actually using four hundred
that's because it has a eight parallel
but if you do eighty times eighty
enter
you can also use a calculator just by opening the chat and typing equals space and then the calculation you want to do
so you can see it's supposed to be say six hundred forty
but we have to account also for the discount which is sixty two
uh, so we have sixty two five
and now you get four hundred
that zero zero zero zero six is the float
so you can see the math, math out
so if we use this one only to crush ores
(a four under pipe?) which is half of a small bronze pipe will be enough
but of course we are going to power other machines
and someday we will probably macerate something that will take more steam than this pipe can carry
but for the moment, i think it's better to chip out a little bit on pipes
and later on when it's an issue
craft some bigger pipes and repurpose the old pipes
and you also have to be careful about that
because unlike single block
if a multi block runs out of steam
it won't simply restart the process
but it will power fail and void whatever it was processing
so, you actually do lose items if those multi blocks run out of steam
but that's the mechanism you're going to have to deal multiple times with
if that happens and you want to be a little bit more careful
one way is to open the control panel and reduce the parallel
because parallel is what causes the cost to really increase
so if you lower the parallel, you will also lower the energy consumption
but of course the best solution is to use bigger pipes
and to increase your power production
here i have two boilers now
and now that our workshop is really well set
we can finally start working on the brick blast furnace
now this is quite expensive
so you probably want a few tips on how to deal with this
i mean the first tip was to get all of the steam multiblocks
but let's see how to use those at the best way possible
and the main thing is that it looks
like you need a lot of clay
but you don't actually need any clay
clay is required for two things
one is bricks and one is clay dust for the concrete
but instead of collecting clay in normal way
it's way better to collect terracotta and then macerate it
terracotta for the clay dust
and bricks from a dungeon for the brick dust
if you are lucky but not even too much lucky
you can find
can find a Canyon biome which basically has (warm?) mountains made out of Terracotta
that biome looks orange and reddish
it's not too hard to find
but i didn't explore much this playthrough
so i didn't find any
you can also find some on mountain biome
which has still a lot of that stuff
so just collect it and then macerate
for the bricks just look for a brick dungeon
you can take all of the bricks on the house above
but once you collect all of those
there is still a lot of bricks
did they have this one too
OK, and there are still a lot of bricks under this dungean
have been told that there are like there are 1000 and even more blocks
it depends on where it spawns
depending on the (Epsilon?) at which is spawner
it can be deeper and thus have more bricks
this is a relatively easy to find dungeon usually
so it shouldn't be hard to find
i already found two of those in this playthrough
but usually you can find a lot of those dungeons
it's not hard to find
look around a lot
you can find good stuff in those dungeons too
to macerate one of those bricks, it takes one second to get one dust
to macerate the brick, it takes twenty times as much to get one quarter
and then you just use the good machines to stock up your inventory with the main parts of the brick blast furnaces
then my suggestion is to fill up your inventory with water buckets and just craft the thing
now, it used to be life saving using the forestry worktable
because that will save your recipe and craft nicely
but nowadays we got NEI auto crafting
and then you just start spam crafting as many bricks as you can
now, as you can see i'm crafting way more bricks than the quest book asks for
and that's because of course, one brick blast furnace will be basically useless
you will want, i would say, a minimum of four brick blast furnaces
that's the minimum i will get
then usually work towards twelve or even sixteen brick balst furnaces
but there are many things you can do in this modpack
so while you wait for this
this is an awfully slow process
it takes six minutes per each ingot of steel per each furnace
so with four brick blast furnaces, you don't get even one steel ingot per minute
you get less
you need six brick blast furnaces just to get one ingot of steel per minute
and you will want a lot of steel
so get a lot of brick blast furnaces
by the way we build those brick blast furnaces all of the way back there because those make a lot of pollution
you can disable pollution in configuration
but i like to keep it enabled as it is by default
so build those a little bit far from your main house if you don't want the pollution to make a disaster
and while the steel is being produced
you can work on other things
for example you can work on crops
which i'm probably going to do in a livestream between episodes
or you can worry about the fuel
talking of which, it is also an issue for our current steam production
right now
i'm burning planks because i can easily chop down the huge rainforest trees that have a lot of logs inside
and then i can simply double the amount of fuel value by crafting those into planks
uh, by the way, to get these rainforest Oak which is a really nice to farm
you can just craft this sapling with a super easy recipe
and it makes a lot of wood
remember to repair your axes between things
but the thing i actually want to use is coke ovens
OK, getting those now is way easier
because you can use this recipe
and you can work with the machines to get more coke ovens
and you can also automate those now
while our brick blast furnaces is slowly working
we can start preparing more coke ovens
and this time we're going to try to automate those nicely
so, after crafting all of the blocks for the coke ovens and the new coke oven hatches that will allow to automate those
never use those
so i'm going to craft a bunch
and so we can wallshare a lot of coke ovens
and then set those new hatches to do the function we want
and once we figure out how we want to layout the pipes
we connect up everything
you have to be careful with item pipes because most likely you only want to use a tin item pipes
and those cannot be removed using an iron ranch
you need an actual steel wrench to be able to remove those
so be careful if you place this
uh, the other issue is that two input ingredients
most likely if you try to use a hopper
which you totally can do
it's going to be slow, i think
because the hopper can only push items one at a time
and the item pipe can only take items every four seconds
it could take a full stack
but the hopper only pushes one
so it gets one item every four seconds
and that's rather slow
it may be good enough for the moment
but if you want
you can just craft a converoy belt
which is a little bit expensive but totally usable
it doesn't even take any steel
and then you add it to the pipe
shift click, import, to make it work properly
and this one will pull one full stack at a time working way better
it's sixteen
but it works sixteen times better than before
by the way, if you misclick and place a plate on a pipe
you can recover it using a crowbar
this mechanic can be quite handy for example with the steam pipes that will hurt you if you get too close
so you can put for example stone plates which is probably the cheapest plate you can make
or i mean if you want you can use any metal
that way you can walk on it nicely
also pipes sometimes bug out a little bit like
not exactly a flat thing when you walk walk over it
so maybe sometimes it glitch out
so maybe you want to put a plate on it
so you can walk really nicely on pipes if you do that
anyways, now we can go back to our currently manual farm
in the future we will automate this
but for the moment it's relatively easy to just chop down those huge trees like that
drop the wood into drawer
and it will slowly make charcoal that we can use on our brick balst furnaces
those coke ovens will also produce creosote oil as we saw at the beginning of the series
and we can use that creosote oil into a fluid burning boiler
which will turn all of that creosote oil into steam
and now we can just build more brick blast furnaces and maybe work on our crops
as soon as we will have enough steel
we can just move on to the next age
which is LV
basically all we need to move on to the next tier is just a little bit of steel
but i think this stuff are really counts as electricity
so this is going to be for the next episode
and with that, i think i'm going to close here
see you next time
bye bye
欢迎大家回来
今天我们将从GTNH教给我们的最有价值的一课开始
倚老卖老
仅仅因为你开启了一种更有效率的做事方式
这并不意味着你必须马上开始使用它
事实上，在上一集里，我们发现我们可以从同样的矿石中得到三倍数量的盘子，通过使用这些蒸汽机器。
问题是，虽然我们通过使用这些机器获得了更好的产量
这些机器也非常慢。
所以，我们将忽略这些机器，回到旧的香草熔炉
我们用焦炉剩余的杂酚油为其供电，我们必须以某种方式使用它
使用锤子，反正我们得到了这么多资源，这是一个足够的处理矿石的方法，没什么大不了的。
有了这个，我们有这么多元宝，我们可以用锤子打碎它们。
就这样囤积铁板
虽然我们可以像这样致力于这些时代的主要目标
我们不会用那些铁板来实现这个主要目标
我们使用这些板是为了将我们的单块车间升级为多块车间
我们制作了这么多东西，即使是NEI汽车制作也太慢了。
在制作了一堆零件之后
我们可以开始真正建造一些东西。
所以，我们首先会有一个蒸汽罐
这将作为我们产生的蒸汽的缓冲
我知道这听起来很奇怪，把蒸汽储存在水箱里，它应该会凝结成水。
但不要想太多
嗯，这次我要在我家屋顶上被点燃
因为我要做太阳能锅炉，我最喜欢的发电方式。
但现在就是这样
那我已经准备了两个大的燃烧盒了
我想我会在开始时这样使用它
但很快，我会把这些换成更大的尺寸。
也可以高一个街区
但目前，只有这个。
好吧，你把这个坦克造得越大
越需要加热
我也想要一个更大的坦克。
但我要在完成剩下的之前得到蒸汽压力机。
然后做水
这个的功率可能足以使用那个水箱
但我想马上做更好的水泵。
这个可以处理更多的机器
我们去
我们用管道把它连接起来，这样它就可以得到一些蒸汽来工作。
这个水泵的缺点是需要一些蒸汽来工作
它比使用其他水箱制造更多的水
但它确实需要一点蒸汽形式的能量
然后我们需要一些水来启动这个。
给你。
我们可以开始加热它
再一次，必须达到100度才能产生蒸汽
所以首先记住这个，它越热，产生的蒸汽就越多。
呃还有其他的锅炉
但我喜欢这个。
我们不能忘记用水管
到锅炉
这里我还有一个方便的未来水管。
通常我强烈建议把所有的管道都拿走，让它流动得更好。
好的，一旦蒸汽达到一半
它会开始推进油箱
这个水箱有一些阀门
这个坦克由三个街区组成
有主要的结构块，玻璃，就像更便宜的一样
还有那些阀门可以让你输入/输出
输出只从底部
油箱从底部自动输出
所以你可以在这个底部连接一根管道，水箱会将蒸汽推入管道
但它在侧面或顶部都不会这样做
所以正如我们在底部所说，很快我们就会有一些蒸汽。
然后我们可以把蒸汽输送到机器上
也想保留一些旧机器
但我也要构建多个块
我是说我们已经有那些机器了
所以不妨保留这些几次，我们需要制作一点东西。
那些更大的多块分批工作
但是那些多街区的建造成本也很高。
所以我们不妨开始使用这些小多块来节省一些材料
我们现在可以用新锅炉更容易地供电了
在比赛的这一点上
我们可能还想有一点自动化。
所以，有了这台机器，自动化就包括使用料斗
所以漏斗放入东西，漏斗进入箱子，输出
有了这个，我们现在可以更容易地制造一些更昂贵的机器，这些机器会工作得更好。
我想做的第一个是蒸汽研磨机
那是因为单块maserator基本上不可能使用
只是太慢了
虽然锻锤和合金冶炼厂是一样的，但我暂时会说
你准备好所有需要的方块
只要准备好一切
然后你可以手动构建它
或者你可以制作一台多块结构全息投影仪
然后你点击那个东西，它就为你建造了。
所以我的建议是先弄清楚你想把舱门放在哪里
一旦你决定把舱门放在哪里，就建造机器。
顺便说一句，当你试图建造机器时，你使用的数量会改变机器的层
所以如果你用一个咒语点击
它会做一级机器
如果你点击一叠两个
它会试着做第二层
比如这个多层块第一层是青铜第二层是钢
接下来我们要担心的是连接它的管道
现在弄清楚用哪个管子不太容易
现在你可能只能用青铜管
每个管道都有不同的容量
现在，如果您查看控制器的使用情况，您可以了解它可能需要多少蒸汽
问题是有些食谱比其他食谱使用更多的蒸汽
所以弄清楚使用什么管道可能很棘手。
现在我只是用一些普通的管子
将来我会决定是否使用以及使用什么管道
顺便说一句，现在我也可以升级坦克了。
我已经升级了锅炉，因为这个小锅炉甚至跟不上简单的盒子。
在那里，我们有更大的水箱，有2000桶容量。
你可能要注意的另一件事是这个相当有效
您在此处看到的蒸汽使用情况不是您在查看多块时应该查看的情况
因为这个多块有速度缓冲，蒸汽使用折扣
但最重要的是有些相似之处
因此，如果您查看例如
随机铁矿石
所有的矿石都应该使用相同数量的蒸汽
应该是每秒八十升
但正如你在这里看到的
它实际上使用了四百个
那是因为它有八个平行
但是如果你做八十乘以八十
进入
您也可以使用计算器，只需打开聊天并输入等于空格，然后进行您要进行的计算
所以你可以看到应该是六百四十英镑。
但我们还必须考虑62英镑的折扣。
呃，所以我们有六十二五
现在你得到了四百
那个零零零六是浮点数
所以你可以看到数学，数学出来了
所以如果我们只用这个来粉碎矿石
（一个四下管？）这是一个小青铜管的一半就足够了
但是我们当然会为其他机器提供动力
有一天，我们可能会浸渍一些东西，这些东西需要的蒸汽比这个管道能携带的还要多。
但现在我觉得还是在管子上多修一点比较好
以后有问题的时候
制作一些更大的管道并重新利用旧管道
你也必须小心这一点
因为与单个块不同
如果多块耗尽蒸汽
它不会简单地重新启动进程
但它会断电并使其处理的任何东西无效
所以，如果这些多块耗尽蒸汽，你确实会丢失物品。
但这是你必须多次处理的机制
如果发生这种情况，你想更加小心一点
一种方法是打开控制面板，减少并联
因为平行是导致成本真正增加的原因
所以如果你降低平行度，你也会降低能耗
但当然最好的解决方案是使用更大的管道
并增加您的电力生产
这里我现在有两个锅炉
现在我们的工作室布置得很好
我们终于可以开始研究砖砌高炉了
这很贵。
所以你可能想要一些关于如何处理这个问题的建议。
我的意思是第一个技巧是得到所有的蒸汽多块
但是让我们看看如何以最好的方式使用它们
最重要的是它看起来
就像你需要很多粘土一样
但你实际上不需要任何粘土
粘土需要做两件事
一种是砖块，一种是混凝土的粘土粉尘
但不是以正常方式收集粘土
收集陶土然后浸渍会更好
陶土尘
和地牢里的砖头换砖灰
如果你很幸运，但不是太幸运
你可以找到
可以找到一个峡谷生物群落，基本上有（温暖的？）由兵马俑制成的山脉
那个生物群落看起来是橙色和红色
这并不难找
但我没怎么探索这个游戏
所以我没有找到任何
你也可以在山地生物群系中找到一些
那里还有很多那种东西。
所以只需收集然后浸渍
对于砖块，只需寻找砖块地牢
你可以拿走上面房子上所有的砖头
但是一旦你收集了所有这些
还有很多砖头
他们也有这个吗？
这地牢下面还有很多砖块
被告知有1000个甚至更多的块
这取决于它在哪里产卵
取决于产卵者所在的（Epsilon？）
它可以更深，因此有更多的砖
这通常是一个相对容易找到的地牢
所以应该不难找到
我已经在这个游戏中找到了两个
但通常你可以找到很多这样的地牢
这并不难找
四处看看
你也可以在地牢里找到好东西
浸渍其中一块砖需要一秒钟才能得到一粒灰尘
浸渍砖需要20倍的量才能得到四分之一
然后你就用好的机器用砖高炉的主要部分来储存你的库存。
那么我的建议是用水桶填满你的库存，然后制作这个东西。
过去，利用林业工作台可以拯救生命。
因为这将很好地保存您的食谱和工艺
但现在我们有NEI汽车工艺
然后你就开始垃圾邮件制作尽可能多的砖块。
如你所见我做的砖头比任务书要求的多得多
这当然是因为，一个砖砌高炉基本上是无用的。
你至少需要四个砖砌的高炉
这是我能得到的最低限度。
然后通常朝着十二个甚至十六个砖熔炉的方向努力
但是在这个modpack中你可以做很多事情
所以在你等这个的时候
这是一个非常缓慢的过程
每炉每锭钢锭需要六分钟
用四个砖砌的高炉，你每分钟连一个钢锭都得不到。
你得到的更少
你需要六个砖高炉才能每分钟得到一锭钢
你会需要很多钢铁
所以买很多砖高炉
顺便说一下，我们在后面建那些砖高炉，因为它们会产生很多污染。
您可以在配置中禁用污染
但我喜欢默认启用它
所以如果你不想污染造成灾难，就把它们建在离你主屋稍远一点的地方。
在生产钢铁的同时
你可以做其他事情
例如，您可以在农作物上工作
我可能会在剧集之间的直播中这样做
或者你可以担心燃料
说起来也是我们现在蒸汽生产的一个问题
现在
我在烧木板，因为我可以很容易地砍掉里面有很多原木的巨大雨林树
然后我就可以把它们做成木板把燃料价值翻倍
呃，顺便说一下，为了得到这些雨林橡树，这是一个非常好的农场
你可以用一个超级简单的食谱制作这棵树苗
它能制造很多木头
记住在事物之间修理你的斧头
但我真正想用的是焦炉
好的，现在买这些要容易得多。
因为你可以用这个食谱
你可以和机器一起买更多的焦炉。
你现在也可以自动化这些。
而我们的砖砌高炉正在慢慢运转
我们可以开始准备更多的焦炉
这次我们将尝试很好地自动化这些
所以，在为焦炉和新的焦炉舱口制作了所有的模块后，这些模块将允许自动化
永远不要用那些
所以我要制作一堆
所以我们可以分享很多焦炉。
然后设置这些新舱口来完成我们想要的功能
一旦我们想出如何布置管道
我们连接一切
你必须小心物品管道，因为很可能你只想使用锡物品管道。
那些不能用铁牧场移除的
您需要一个真正的钢扳手才能移除这些
所以如果你放这个要小心
呃，另一个问题是两种输入成分
最有可能的是，如果您尝试使用漏斗
你完全可以做到。
我想会很慢
因为漏斗一次只能推送一个商品
物品管道只能每四秒取一次物品。
可能需要一大堆
但是漏斗只推一个
所以它每四秒就有一件商品。
这相当缓慢
目前可能已经足够好了
但如果你愿意
你可以制作一条转轮皮带
这有点贵，但完全可用。
它甚至不需要任何钢铁
然后你把它添加到管道中
shift点击，导入，使其正常工作
这个会一次拉一个完整的堆栈，效果更好。
是十六
但效果比以前好16倍
顺便说一句，如果你按错了，把盘子放在管子上
你可以用撬棍把它找回来
这个机械师可以很方便例如与蒸汽管道会伤害你如果你太接近
所以你可以放例如石盘，这可能是你能做的最便宜的盘子。
或者我的意思是，如果你愿意，你可以使用任何金属
这样你可以很好地在上面行走
管道有时bug有点像
当你走过它时，它不完全是一个平坦的东西
所以也许有时它会出故障
所以也许你想放个盘子在上面
如果你这样做，你可以在管道上走得很好。
不管怎样，现在我们可以回到我们目前的人工农场了
未来我们将实现自动化
但就目前而言，像这样砍倒那些大树相对容易
把木头扔进抽屉
它会慢慢制造木炭，我们可以用在砖炉上。
这些焦炉也会产生杂酚油，就像我们在系列开始时看到的那样
我们可以将杂酚油用于液体燃烧锅炉
它会把所有的杂酚油变成蒸汽
现在我们可以建造更多的砖砌高炉，也许可以种植庄稼。
只要我们有足够的钢铁
我们可以进入下一个时代
哪个是LV
基本上我们只需要一点点钢铁就能进入下一层
但我觉得这东西真的算电
所以这将是下一集的内容
就这样我想我要结束了
下次见
拜拜